Guide to the Larry Neal papers
New York Public Library
- Writings
  - Scripts
    The Script subseries, 1972-1980 (2 lin. ft.), is composed of playscripts Neal authored and includes annotated and incomplete versions (dated and undated), final and early drafts, and fragments, as well as reviews for several of his produced plays. Among the plays included in the collection are The Glorious Monster in the Bell of the Horn, In an Upstate Motel, Their Eyes Were Watching God, The Blue Monday Number, Daddy Salvation, Deep River, as well as some which are unidentified.
    - The Glorious Monster in the Bell of the Horn
      - Final Version, July 10, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Annotated, July 10, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Annotated, September 14, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 3-5)
      - 1976 (Box 9, Folder 6-8)
      - Annotated, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
      - Incomplete, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
      - Early Script - Characters in a Play - Revised, Incomplete, February 3, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Annotated and Incomplete, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 14-15)
      - Various Versions, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - Early Script Entitled Tag Taking - Annotated (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
      - Incomplete (Box 10, Folder 4-8)
      - Incomplete, Annotated (Box 10, Folder 9-12)
      - Fragments (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
      - Annotated Fragments (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
      - Manuscripts and Annotated Fragments (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Annotated Fragments (Box 11, Folder 4-5)
      - Revised Scene and Notes (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Reviews, Correspondence and Programs, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Contract With Henry Street Settlement, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - In an Upstate Motel
      - Annotated, Incomplete (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Annotated (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Annotated (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Annotated, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Notes (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - 1980 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Clippings, Program, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Their Eyes Were Watching God
      - Draft (Box 12, Folder 8-9)
      - Annotated, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 10-11)
      - Draft -, September 4, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 12-14)
    - Avatar Enterprises
      - Their Eyes Were Watching God - Film, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 15-16)
      - Revision, July 17, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - The Bamboo Bar - Script (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Black History (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - The Blue Monday Number
      - Story Outline (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Story Incomplete (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Outline Revised -, November 28, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Film Outline -, November 10, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Filmscript, Incomplete (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Script (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - Incomplete (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Book of Numbers - Story Synopsis of the Even Chapters (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Buddy Byrd's Inner City Blues - Play Idea (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Daddy Salvation
      - Script (Box 13, Folder 14-15)
      - Script- Fragments (Box 13, Folder 16)
      - Incomplete, Annotated (Box 13, Folder 17)
      - Incomplete (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - The Death of Boogie Woogie (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Deep River - Drafts, Incomplete (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Ley - Script Outline (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Lenox Avenue Sunday - Script, Notes (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Revolutionary Violence and the Negro Leadership - Script (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Ethnic Culture Television Series, Treatment/Script (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Script Fragments and Notes (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
    - Script Fragments (Box 14, Folder 7-8)
  - Screenplays
    The Screenplay subseries, 1967-1979 (.8 lin. ft.) contains screenplays (typescripts and handwritten), story and film outlines, treatments, film ideas (dated and undated), proposals and budgets for the many screenplays Neal authored, only a few of which were produced. The film titles include “Haig's Last Case,” Holy Days (produced) (co-authored with Evan Walker and published in 1970), Ramadan Lover, Saga of the Slave Ship Amistad, and A Truant's End, (produced) and some that are unidentified. Neal was also involved in a number of film projects. Those contained in the collection are Harlem Studio Visuals, Revolution in Black America, and Newark Television Station/Urban Communications Institute.
    - All African Games - Film Ideas - Incomplete (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Beirut Fiasco - Film Treatment (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - The Cafe Blue Majestic - Film Treatment - Incomplete (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Cane River - Film Idea (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Black Art!!! - Film Outline, 1968(?) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Cosmos and the Old Musician, Buddy - Story Outline (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - The Disciple - Film Treatment (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Ghosts - Film Treatment (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Haig's Last Case (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - With Hoyt Fuller (Television Drama) - Film Treatment, 1975
      - Story Outline - Incomplete (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Holy Days
      - With Evan Walker - Screenplay, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Playscript - Incomplete (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - Harlem Audio-Visuals - Filmscript, Story (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - Story (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Story, Early Revision - Fragment (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - Script, Production Schedule - Film Project -, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - Film Script - Budget Estimate (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - Screenplay - Review, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - In Search of Improvisation - Filmscript, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - In Search of Jazz - Film Outline (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Jihad (Holy War) - A Piece for Dance (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Jim Crow, Shine and Stepinfechit - Filmscript (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Kansas City Layover - Script - Notes, 1979(? (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Labor Series - Court Room Testimony - Script, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - The Man Who Lived Underground - Film Project, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Meeting Point: Afro-Americans Look at Zaire - Film Proposal (Avatar Enterprises), 1974 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - More Than Machines - Picture Budget Detail (Avatar Enterprises), 1974 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Ramadan Lover
      - Outline and Treatment - Incomplete First Draft, May 20, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - Incomplete, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Raymond, Iris, Eddie - Incomplete (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
    - Saga of the Slaveship Amistad - Film Treatment/Outline, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Slave Ship Amistad - Manuscript, Reference Articles (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - The Sun Song of Cosmos T. Bird - Film Treatment (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - The Transfiguration of Joe Eclipse: An Outline for a Music-Drama - With Evan Walker (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - A Truant's End (Box 16, Folder 13-15)
    - Visions of Harlem - Film Idea - Holy Days Film Company, Inc. (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - The Way September Came Down - Film Treatment (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - No Title - Fragment (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Untitled Script - Fragment (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Film Projects
      - Harlem Audio Visual-Coalition/Jobs, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Harlem Audio Visuals, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Newark Television Station/Urban Communication Institute, Inc., 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 3-7)
      - Revolution in Black America
        - Scripts, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 8)
        - 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 9)
        - News Releases, Correspondence, Clippings, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Poems
    The Poems subseries, 1974-1979 (.8 lin. ft.), consists of both published and unpublished poems and includes typescripts (some annotated), fragments, and holograph versions.
    - Poems (Box 18, Folder 1-14)
    - Poem Fragments (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Anthologies and Other Publication Projects
    The Anthologies and Other Publication Projects subseries, 1961-1978, (1.2 lin. ft.), includes selections for the anthology Black Fire: An Anthology of Afro-American Writing(New York, William Morrow & Co., 1968) which Neal co-edited with Amiri Baraka, consisting of the essays, poetry, short stories and drama the co-editors considered for inclusion. Not all pieces submitted were actually published in Black Fire, and the book contains submissions not represented in the collection. The published books of poetry (represented by manuscripts) are Hoodoo Hollerin' Bebop Ghosts(Howard University Press, 1974) and Black Boogaloo: Notes of Black Liberation(San Francisco, Journal of Black Poetry Press, 1969). Many of the poems here such as Neal's Shine series were anthologized in a number of works. Other poems were published once or remain unpublished. The manuscripts for sections of Neal's New Space: Critical Essays on American Culture (published posthumously) can be found in this series. There are also several manuscripts, outlines and proposals for unpublished books including works on jazz and a biography of Max Roach, as well as Black American Music, black cultural criticism, and the social history of popular Afro-American music. In addition, this subseries encompasses the published version of Notes on Black Liberation, articles Neal wrote, and copies of the journal's Confrontation and Extension which he edited. Included are photocopies of some of his published poems, clippings of articles he wrote, and articles in which his work is mentioned.
    - Black Fire
      - Correspondence, Biographies, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - William Morrow Publishers, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Contracts, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Contents List, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Reviews, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Authors A-B, 1961-1966 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Authors C, 1966, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Authors D-G, 1965-1966 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Authors H, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Authors I-L, 1966, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Authors M (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Authors N-R, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - Authors Sa-Sp, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Authors St-T, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - Authors W, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Black Boogaloo (Notes on Black Literature)
      - Publication, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Annotated Manuscript (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Book Review, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Hoodoo Hollerin' Bebop Ghost
      - Annotated Manuscripts (Box 20, Folder 4-10)
      - Photocopy Manuscript (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Annotated Photocopies (Box 20, Folder 12-13)
      - “Shine” Stories (Box 20, Folder 14-16)
      - Hoodoo Hollerin' Bebop Ghosts/and Other Visions (Box 20, Folder 17)
      - Galley, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 18)
      - Dust Jacket and Flap-Copy (Box 20, Folder 19)
      - Review, Errata, and Program, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 20)
      - Royalty Statement, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - New Space: Critical Essays on American Culture
      - The Rise of Black Consciousness in the Sixties (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - The Rise of the Black Consciousness in the 70's, 1970's (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - The Galaxy Around Harlem - Incomplete (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Notes on Ethos (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Reactionary and Revolutionary Positions - Literary Criticism (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Notes on K. Burke (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Black American Music - Book (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - The Black Church - Outline (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Black Boxing and Ali/Johnson - Outline (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Black Culture Criticism - Outline for a Book and Essay (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Black History - Forward to Book - Incomplete (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Exodus - Migration Novel - Notes (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Jazz is a Four Letter Word: The Biography of Max Roach - By Max Roach and Larry Neal
      - Typescript, Notes Draft, ca. 1979 (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - Typescript, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - Chapter Outline and Notes (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Jazz Manuscript, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 16-17)
    - Precis `Boxing As Drama' by Larry Neal and Seymour Gray - Book Outline (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Social History of Popular Afro-American Music - Book Proposal (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Six Black Horses - Story Outline - Novel by Nolan Davis, outline by Larry Neal (Box 21, Folder 20)
      - Articles
        - “A-B,”, 1964-1978 (Box 22, Folder 1)
        - “D,”, 1966-1981 (Box 22, Folder 2)
        - “E-F,”, 1967-1972 (Box 22, Folder 3)
        - “G,”, 1978-1980 (Box 22, Folder 4)
        - “I-J,”, 1965-1975 (Box 22, Folder 5)
        - “M-N,”, 1965-1969 (Box 22, Folder 6)
        - “P-V,”, 1964-1970 (Box 22, Folder 7)
        - “W-Z,”, 1964-1974 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Editor - Confrontation and Extension, 1971, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - News Clippings, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Mentions, 1968-1985 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Short Stories
    The Short Stories subseries, 1973, n.d. (.6 lin. ft.), consists of complete and incomplete typescripts, most unpublished, in addition to fragments and notes. Titles of a few stories are The Assassins, Blue Berry Hill, Deaths in the John, Our Bright Tomorrows, and Rahada/A Love Song for the Cosmic People.
    - Abdul Avatar and the Sun Sister's Song (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Afro Freedom Alliance (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Agnes, Rose, and Red Eye (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - The Assassins, 1967, 1968, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Blue Berry Hill (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Blues Stretch - Tentative Scenes - Incomplete, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Come Sunday (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Dawoud Bey - Fragment (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Deaths in the John, - Story Sketch, ca. 1973 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - First Entry: Scorpio, Aries Raises (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Honky Tonk Bud (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Iris, Mabel, André - (Goodnight, Congressman), 1968 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - New York War - Incomplete (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Number Runner (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Oba and the Moon (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Our Bright Tomorrows (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Professor Chauncey E. Worthington's Diary - Incomplete (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Rahada/A Love Song for the Cosmic People (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Sea Song and Other Fragments (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Selma - Incomplete (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Warrior Biography (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Where is the Professor? (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Music - Incomplete (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Incomplete (Box 24, Folder 24-26)
    - Story Fragments (Box 25, Folder 1-8)
    - Story Fragments and Notes (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Interviews
    The Interviews subseries, 1971-1980 (.8 lin. ft.), is comprised of manuscripts, outlines, notes and questions for interviews with the following individuals: Muhammad Ali on his 1974 fight with George Foreman in Zaire, Rap Brown, John Coltrane, Langston Hughes, Melvin Van Peebles, Max Roach, Sun Ra, and James Van Der Zee.
    - Muhammed Ali on Foreman Fight - Questions for Interview (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Black Theatre - Incomplete (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - John Coltrane Biography - Outline and Fragment, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - H. Rap Brown - Fragment (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Larry Neal Interview on Langston Hughes, 1978 (? (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - An Interview with Melvin Van Peebles (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - An Interview with Sun God - [Sun Ra] - Incomplete (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - An Interview with Mr. and Mrs. James Vanderzee, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Notes
    The Notes subseries, 1971-1980 (.8 lin. ft.), contains Neal's notes about writers and poets, and writing projects with which he was involved including Ishmael Reed's Mumbo Jumbo as well as notes Neal took based upon his readings, conferences he attended, and ideas he had for his writings. Many notes appear in notebooks, others are on individual sheets of paper.
    - Notes for Classes - Writer and Poets, 1971 1975-1976 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - First Love - Direction Notes (Dance?), Stories, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Mexico, Writers (Addresses), 1975-1976 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Projects, 1978-1979 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Ishmael Reed's `Mumbo Jumbo”, Plagiarism, Camas - Notebook, 1978-1980 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Notes (Box 28, Folder 1-14)
- D.C. Commission On The Arts And Humanities
  The series provides a limited view of Neal's role as Executive Director of this agency. The scope of the material includes, an incomplete set of minutes of Board of Directors' meetings, memoranda, transcript of an interview with Neal, several proposals such as those for a District of Columbia Solidarity Project, and a National Black Theatre, handouts from an employment and career workshop, annual and other reports, and printed material pertaining to programs sponsored by the commission.
  - Minutes - Board of Directors Meetings, 1977-1978 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda, 1977-1979 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Personnel, Budgets, 1977-1978 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Transition Meeting Notes, November 9, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - On the Road to Transition - I (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Transition Report - II (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Report, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Notebook - Meeting Notes, 1978-1979 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Appointment Book, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Interview with Larry Neal, Letter of Resignation, 1977-1979 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - National Assembly of State Arts Agencies, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Proposals for District of Columbia Cultural Solidarity Project, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Proposal for the National Black Theatre (A Theatre for the Black Nation), n.d. (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Proposals and Budgets, 1977-1979 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Proposals, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Proposals, ca. 1978 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Arts D.C. - Employment and Career Workshop, July 14, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - General, 1971-1977 - (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - General, 1977-1979 - (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - General, 1978 - (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - General, 1978 - (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Printed Material, 1977-1979 (Box 30, Folder 6)
- Reference Material
  - Subject File
    The Subject File subseries, 1965-1980 (2 lin. ft.) reflects Neal's broad range of interest in black related issues. Examples of the subject files are the Black Panther, Party, Black Power, Congress of African Peoples, Eddie Ellis, Second World Black and African Festival of Arts and Culture (FESTAC), Harlem Urban Renewal, LeRoi Jones (Neal used both LeRoi Jones and Amiri Baraka; during processing the decision was made to keep Neal's usage for folder headings), Black Power conferences, the Revolutionary Action Movement, and the 1965 and 1967 riots/rebellions that took place in Detroit, Los Angeles, Newark, New York, and New Haven. The subject files contains news clippings, articles, other printed and typed reports, leaflets, and other printed material. In this subseries can be found several papers prepared for the Primer Congreso de la Cultura Negra de las America held in Columbia, South America (1977), including papers by Abdias do Nascimento and Antonio Viera de Silva.
    - African Nationalist, 1965-1967 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - African People's Conference, December 26-27, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Bibliographies (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Black Aesthetic, 1971-1979 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Black Art, 1970-1974, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Black Dramatists Project - Conference, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Black Elite, 1965 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Black Elite, 1966-1967 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Black Filmmaker Foundation, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Black History Museum Umum Newsletter, 1976-1978 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Black Music Association - Conference, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Black Panther Party, 1966-1967, ca.1971, n.d (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - New York Panther 21 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Black Power
      - Articles, Statements, etc., 1966-1967, 1969, n.d (Box 31, Folder 14)
      - Conferences, 1967-1968 (Box 31, Folder 15)
      - Articles About, 1966-1967 (Box 31, Folder 16)
      - Miscellaneous Articles, 1967-1970 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Black Studies (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Black Theatre
      - 1965-1969 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - ca. 1970 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Blacks in Films, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Congress of African Peoples - Kuumba House, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 6-7)
    - Congress of African Peoples
      - 1970 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Creativity Workshop, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Ideological Statement, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Congress on Black Culture in the Americas (Columbia, South America), August 1977
    - General Information (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Diouf, Mam Biram - Pour un Nouvel Order Culturel Mondial (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Nascimento, Abdias do Afro-Brazilian Ethnicity and International Policy (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Rodrigues Al Ves, Sebastiao Somos Todos Iguais Perante a Lei (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Viera de Silva, Antonio The Cultural Contribution of Black People to the Construction of Modern Brazil (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Watts, A. Faulkner - The Black Slave Woman: Protagonist for Freedom (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Congress of Racial Equality, 1966-1968 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Coordinating Council of Literary Magazines
      - General Information, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 12)
      - Umbra, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Cricket - Black Music Journal (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Detroit Shooting- New Republic of Africa, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Education, 1967, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Eddie Ellis, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Ellison, Ralph, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Feet - Dance Magazine, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - FESTAC (Second World Black and African Festival of Arts and Culture)
      - 1966-1976 (Box 33, Folder 20)
      - Speeches by Bernard W. Bell, John Henrik (Box 33, Folder 21)
      - Clarke, and Ronald W. Walters, 1977
    - Films - Cast and Credits of The Lost Man and Slaves, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 22)
    - Harlem Cultural Council - Harlem Writers' Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Harlem Urban Renewal Proposal, 1970
      - 1970 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - n.d (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Hatch-Billops Oral History Collection of Black Artists, 1972-1973 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Billie Holiday Estate, 1954-1962 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Joans, Ted, 1971-1975 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Jones, LeRoi, 1968 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Jordan, Norman/Black Cultural Network, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Roy Lewis - Autobiography, ca. 1972 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Music, 1974-1976 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - National Association of Black Media Producers, ca. 1975 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - National Black Theatre, Inc., Touring Program, 1978 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Creativity Workshops, Elma Lewis School, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 14)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - National Independent Political Party for Afro-Americans - Minutes, September 3-4, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - National Urban League, 1960, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - New Lafayette Theatre, ca. 1971 (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Organization for the Development and Advancement of the Cultural Black Arts, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Pan African Artists' Alliance, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Obituaries- John Coltrane, Langston Hughes, Billy Strayhorn, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Charlie Parker Estate, 1961-1976 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Progressive Labor Party, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Revolutionary Action Movement, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Riots
      - Detroit, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 5-6)
      - Los Angeles, 1965 (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - New York, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - Newark, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - New Haven, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Riots - General, 1966-1967 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Rod Rodgers Dance Company, 1974-1977 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Schools- I.S. 201 School Strike, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - William Strickland, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 1)